A third of the questions that your
customers are actually asking have zero
search volume. Not low, but zero. Which
means the keyword research tool you're
using is not going to show you these
questions. And finding these missing
questions is a big part of the SEO game
now because you don't want to rank for a
specific keyword now. You want to rank
for a topic. The way to become the
topical authority figure in that is
answer as many of these questions as you
can. That's how you'll get cited and
recommended by things like GPT search
and Google AI overviews. The good thing
is that these questions are already
written down. You just need to know
where to look. They're in things like
Reddit, yours, and your customers
reviews, autocomplete, people also ask,
fan out queries, and a few more things.
Problem is that to get all these
questions and then to know what to do
with them can be quite time consuming.
But I've built a skill and a workflow
with Claude that's going to help you
extract all these golden questions from
Reddit. People also ask autocomplete and
a bunch more places. And it's even going
to tell you exactly what you need to do
with them. Should they be added as an
FAQ at the bottom of your service page?
Should it be a blog? Or should it even
be a video? Let's get directly into it.
A couple of things we need to understand
before we really get stuck into this.
The tools that you're using, they're not
necessarily wrong. They're just
incomplete. We need these to find these
questions that a lot of people are
asking but most SEO tools are not going
to show. And then we also need to
understand that there are specifications
that these questions fall under. Now
there are more types of keywords I'll
admit than just
transactionalformational.
But I think I like to keep it simple. So
with all these keyword research or
question research I should say rather we
also need to understand that it needs to
be classified in a transactional keyword
or question or anformational keyword
meaning well does this question kind of
need to be on a service page because if
people are asking this then they're
probably ready to purchase or does it
need is it anformational question or
keyword meaning do we need to create
content around that so we're answering
this and then we need to understand well
what kind kind of content is it is it a
blog post or will it be a video and For
the most part, all of these questions
can be found on Reddit, your reviews.
People also ask, and fan out queries.
So, the problem is that by default,
Claude doesn't have access to all of
these things. Now, if you've seen the
channel, you know that I can connect
Claude for data for SEO to Claude, which
I've done so many videos about this that
people literally think I work data for
SEO, which I don't. I just really like
the service. So, I'm going to leave a
video for you below into how to connect
Claude with data for SEO because you
need that connection and you also need
one more connection. But don't worry if
you're just using this the for the first
time and you're only connecting this one
thing, it's going to be absolutely free.
That other thing is Zio. So, what Zonio
allows us to do is to connect Claude to
a bunch of different things. So, if I go
to Zio
and I go to the products, I can see that
I can connect it to all these platforms.
for the most part they're social media,
but I can connect it also to good old
Reddit and it allows us to scrape Reddit
really, really well. You want to go and
create yourself an account. By the way,
the pricing here, as I said, is really
handy because if you want to connect two
accounts, it's completely free. Create
an account, use link below, and what you
want to do is go to create a new
connection. We we want to find Reddit,
and we want to connect or authenticate
our Reddit account with this. I'm going
to allow.
Now, with that authenticated, we need to
connect Zerno to Claude. So, now then
Claude has access to Reddit. To do that,
we need to go to customize. We need to
go to add new, sorry, connectors down
here, we need to go to add new custom
connector. And in this input field here,
the remote MCP server URL, you want to
paste this mcp.zerno.com/mcp.
The name for this can be whatever zone
and [music] I'm going to add. You don't
need to do any of the advanced settings
as long as you are connected to Zio with
the same browser because then it'll be
very easy to authenticate all this
thing. You can see here that I can just
connect it. It's going to do one more
pop-up asking me if I really want to
connect it.
And there you go.
So now with this connected and data for
SEO connected, if you want a quick
tutorial for that, it's about a minute
long. I'll leave a link for that in the
video description below. you are set to
go because this requires kind quite an
extensive kind of step-by-step process
to extract this and then to make sense
of it all. I have a uh zipped file that
I'm going to give you in the video
description below. It's going to be
available in our free community. You can
download it and it's just kind of a
keyword language is essentially a skill
plus a set of really detailed
instructions for all this. So with that
zip file in Claude, you can now say
things like, "I want you to uh unzip the
file, understand all of the
instructions, and then run those
instructions on the plumbing market in
Austin, Texas."
The more broad you go here, the better,
which usually is something that I do not
say, but in this case, we want to find
as many of these questions that people
are asking.
Once you give that a couple of minutes
to run, you'll have this report. And I
want to go through this so you
understand what to do with it. So you
don't get stuck with a report and go,
"Great, a bunch of questions that I
don't know what to do with." Your report
should look a little bit like this.
It'll be very different in terms of the
data. Obviously, depending on the niche,
the industry, and the location you got
it to kind of review. Sometimes you'll
have very little data. I specifically
chose uh Texas and plumbing, by the way,
so that I did have some good data so I
could show you. So if you run this in a
very niche uh kind of area or for a very
niche service, just bear in mind you
might not have the same kind of outputs.
But I want to go through what these
things kind of mean and what we need to
do with them as a result. So this will
give you an overview of where it got the
questions right from 52 uh Reddit
threads across 111 subreddits. That is a
lot of information. Great. Claude
filtered through all of that. People
also ask autocomplete and fan out
queries. Now, these all make sense, but
what is a fan out query? If you're new
to this channel, let me explain that
very quickly. A fan out query is
something that is just in the AI search
engines, meaning Google AI overviews and
chatbt. When you ask one of these search
engines with access to AI a question, it
doesn't just grab that question and go,
"No problems, I'll do research on it.
Leave it with me." Depending on the
complexity of the question, it will ask
itself internal subsequent related
questions about that. These are fan out
queries that are hidden but thanks to
data for SEO they are uncovered and then
the AI will research all these
subsequent questions so that it can
distill a much better answer for you
because some of these related questions
might be asking questions that you are
there's a high probability of you asking
next part of the goal here is to
understand what these fan out queries
are so we can answer them. So obviously
the AR search engines
use our information to create their
answers and therefore we get cited.
[snorts]
If we look at this report, you're going
to get a few types of qu how these
questions should be routed, how they
should be answered. There's FAQ
questions, meaning look, they're
standalone. You're not going to rank for
it by itself, but you probably need it
somewhere on your services pages.
There's a link to a full post, meaning
you need to answer this in a service
page. But if you want to, you can link
somewhere within this answer to a post
itself that answers this in detail. A
post says, well, it needs to be its own
page, its own blog post answered in
detail. And also a video, why on earth a
video? Well, the search intent of
something, meaning how people want this
question to be answered, will change
drastically depending on the question.
For example, if I search, and you can
search this now in your browser. If I
search something like how to do a bicep
curl, one of the first things that I see
is videos, videos, videos. This is
citing a video. And if I go down, it's
videos and more videos. And also, you
can see that the tabs here change to
show you the next tab to be more short
videos because it thinks there's a
[snorts] very large probability that
what you're after isn't an answer like
this, but it's actually a tutorial of a
short form video. And this happens a lot
more than you realize. So the goal here
is to also understand that sometimes it
doesn't need to be a blog post or an FAQ
section. Sometimes it needs to be a
quick video, which means yes,
unfortunately you need to get in front
of the camera and record yourself.
Ideally, it also that same uh video you
turn it into a blog post and you embed
the video in the blog post, but that's
for another tutorial. So with that
understood, let's keep going through our
document here. So here it understood.
All right. Well, here are all the main
keywords that are probably going to make
your services pages. Things like roof
replacement, roof repair, storm and hail
damage. And you see, if you see here,
great roof replacement FAQ blocks on
this page. Meaning on your main services
page, because these is more more than
not a transactional keyword. How much
does a new roof cost? You should answer
it in your service page, but you should
probably link to a full post answering
that in detail
as opposed to
how do I know if I need a new roof? That
needs to be a dedicated blog post that
you need to answer.
Let's continue doing this. Right? So,
here in roof repair,
can you fix a roof leak without
replacing the whole roof? that question.
All it needs to do is to be answered in
that service page as opposed to how do I
stop a roof leaking until the roofer
arrives. That probably needs to be a
short form video. When everything when
anything is a video, I would also
recommend just write a quick blog post
about it, but concentrate on the video
first and so on and so forth. So, it
just kind of tells you exactly what you
need to do. Again, this is vastly going
to change for you depending on the
industry that you chose. further all the
way down. What we have here is [music] a
analysis of the questions or the
comments
from your and your competitors reviews
because whilst these aren't questions,
the comments here deem that you should
answer questions around these comments.
For example, here for the term or the
topic, explain what they were doing.
There's a lot of negative sentiment
around this, but there's also a positive
sentiment around this. So already we
want to make sure that we answer
questions on explaining how things are
done. So what is our working process
like? Right? These are the questions you
should be answering. Here's another one.
So for the term had to come back and
redo it, there's a lot more negative
sentiment around this as opposed to
positive sentiment. Meaning, I probably
want to make sure that I preempt this
and say if the work does what happens if
the work goes wrong after a couple of
weeks, maybe the busted pipe that we
fixed as a plumber, you know, busted
again after a couple of weeks. Well, we
should probably have some sort of
question that we're answering in our
content saying, "Yes, we'll come back if
something happens." Things like this. I
hope that one made sense, but that one
is really, really important because from
this, you see what people are actually
really worried about when they're
getting their service. So, this is kind
of adding a lot of trust to those FAQs
that you write. Now, you probably
noticed that a lot of these are blog
posts, most of these. So, link to full
blog post or a blog post on its own. And
you might be thinking, well, this is
great, but how do I write a blog post
that ensures it's going to get cited by
the AI search engines? That's a whole
video on its own. If you want a detailed
tutorial on how to do that completely
for free, I'll leave a link for you
below to our AI search Kickstarter. This
is part of our free community. Lesson
six, there is a lesson that is how to
write content that the AI search engine
loves. This is following best practices
that we've learned and we've researched
and we've proven over the past 2 years
on how to write content with AI that the
AI search engines will love. Meaning the
highest probability that's going to get
you cited and mentioned and treated you
like the topical authority figure within
this niche.
And again, for full transparency,
running that report does have a cost,
but a very little one. The only cost is
really coming from data for SEO because
there is a call you're making for that
or a couple actually. There is a price
for that. But the reason why I like data
for SEO is because it's so effective.
All that information that we got from
the report that I showed you is gold.
It's so valuable. And the only thing
that it cost us was around 59. I've done
this uh flow a couple of times and it
ranges from 50 cents all the way to like
80 cents, but I find that the average is
around 59 cents. So, not too bad,
particularly when you're not going to be
running this all the time if it's just
for your business. Once every 6 months
will be great because you should get
some new questions when they come up.
Again, the main thing that I want you to
take away from this is that you're not
just trying to rank for a keyword. We're
trying to rank for a topic. And in order
for us to rank for a topic, we need to
understand what are all the questions
that people are asking so we can answer
them and we can rank for this topic. I
hope you like this video. Again, all the
resources will be in our free community
link to that below. The file is there.
If you don't see it because you're on
mobile, make sure you swipe and the file
will be right there. Thanks for
watching. I'll catch you in the next
one.